Guide to the California Menus Collection M2125
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
California Menu Collection
1866-1980s
early-to-mid 20th century
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
M2125
1.3 Linear Feet (2 boxes, 2 flat boxes)
Collection of menus from California, especially San Francisco and Los Angeles.
Scope and Contents
A collection of menus from events and restaurants from California, with a few from other states and countries. In all, more than 120 items ranging from 1866 to the 1980s, with most from the early-to-mid 20th century. More than half of the menus have specific dates. Arrangement is approximately geographical from north to south, with series for San Francisco, Los Angeles and the Bohemian Club among others. All items are menus unless otherwise stated; there are also a few advertisements, invitations, and postcards, as well as a set of nametags and a placemat. Condition is generally fair. Many have holes from scrapbook removal as well as rusty paperclip stains. Some silk and other bindings are untied, missing, or disintegrating.
Highlights include banquet menus from early visits by sitting U.S. Presidents to California, pre-1900 event menus on silk, menus from the 1929 Kyoto Conference, the Panama-California Exposition and Panama-Pacific International Exposition, Disney & 20th Century Fox-related menus from Southern California, and menus from both early and iconic restaurants in SF & LA.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was purchased by Stanford University, Special Collections in 2016.
Related Materials
The California Historical Society holds a California Menu Collection (http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c8qn68hw). The Los Angeles Public Library also has a menu collection (http://www.lapl.org/collections-resources/visual-collections/menu-collection).
Menus -- California; Restaurants -- California
- Series 1. San Francisco menus
  Arrangement
  Menus for the Palace and St. Francis Hotel are grouped first, followed by three Chinatown menus. The remainder of this series has been arranged chronologically, beginning with undated menus.
  - California Commandery (Military Order, Loyal Legion, United States) Year-End Banquet, Hotel St. Francis, 1907-12-14 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Hotel St. Francis dinner, 1930-12-18 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Hotel St. Francis Tea Time, circa 1930s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Mural Room, St. Francis Hotel, 1951-08-07 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Palace Hotel (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Banquet Tendered to Benjamin Harrison, President of the United States By The Citizens of San Francisco. Palace Hotel, 1891-05-01 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ohio Society of California Banquet Tendered to President William McKinley At The Palace Hotel, 1901-05-16 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Scope and Contents
    Two copies, one annotated. The banquet was cancelled due to Mrs. McKinley's illness.
  - Palace Hotel, Christmas [hand painted Chinese-themed cover by LeLong], 1902-12-25 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Luncheon Honoring Old-Time Boxers, Palm Court, Palm Court, Palace Hotel, 1941-06-21 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - State Dinner in Commemoration of the 10th Anniversary of Signing of the Charter of the United Nations. Garden Court, Sheraton-Palace Hotel, 1955-06-25 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - World Branches' Conference Dinner of the English-Speaking Union in the Presence of...Prince Philip, Duke of Edinburgh, Sheraton-Palace Hotel, 1961-11-14 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    With place cards and letter concerning the waiters for the head table.
  - Tao Lee Yun [In English & Chinese] (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Shanghai Low (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Kuo Wah Cafe [In English & Chinese], circa 1952 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Blum's Fountain and Ice Cream Suggestions (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bernstein's Fish Grotto (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - The Manger [menu and postcard] (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Occidental Hotel, pre-1906 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Dodge Brothers [padded, hand-painted], 1887-03-08 (Box 4)
    Dodge Brothers was a stationer & engraver located at 225 Post Street; this menu (for a special event, presumably) lists Ernst H. Ludwig as caterer.
  - The Roof Garden, circa 1930s (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - San Francisco Dental College Annual Banquet, Cosmos Rotisserie, 1902-05-20 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - The Louvre, 1904-01 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - North Beach Thanksgiving Carnival Banquet, Fior d'Italia, 1910-11-27 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Banquet to the President of the United States [William Howard Taft]...by the Directors of the Panama-Pacific International Exposition...on the Occasion of the Ground Breaking Ceremonies, 1911-10-13 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Carnival Night at the Portola-Odeon, 1920-01-15 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Women's Athletic Club, 1931-02-10 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Mark Hopkins, 1931-02-26 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Solari's [two menus], 1931-09-24; 1932-05-11 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - The Front Porch, 1932-05-11 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Bal Tabarin [three menus], [1932]; 1933 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - El Cortez, 1933-03-23 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - The Golden Pheasant, 1937-09-03 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Exposition Flyer. Western Pacific Special Luncheon; Western Pacific Special Dinner [two menus], 1943 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Omar Khayyam's, 1944-08-13 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Club Savoy Theatre Restaurant. Welcome United Nations Conference, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Touchdown Club 2nd Annual Awards Dinner, Marines Memorial Club, 1949-01-11 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - 33rd Annual Conference, National Association of Secretaries of State, Hotel Fairmont, 1950-10 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Series 2. Bohemian Club menus
  - Bohemian Club: Breakfast in Bohemia Encampment, 1910-08-07 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Christmas in Bohemia [Bohemian Club], 1910-12-28 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Dinner in honor of His Admiral Tejiro Koroi, Staff and Executive Officers of His Imperial Japanese Majesty's Training Squadron, The Bohemian Club [San Francisco Chamber of Commerce embossed stamp on cover], 1914-06-10 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Series 3. Northern California menus [Sacramento - Monterey]
  - Roarin' Camp. Eagle Theatre & Danse [sic] Hall. Sacramento Golden Empire Centennial, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Hotel Senator Coffee Shop [Sacramento], 1932-02-17 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Del Webb's Sahara Tahoe Souvenir Menu [Elvis Presley image & advertisement], circa 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Hotel Carlton, Berkeley [advertising pamphlet] (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Woody's Creamery, Berkeley (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Banquet Honoring Joseph R. Knowland [publisher of Oakland Tribune], Athens Athletic Club, Oakland, 1952-05-17 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    Seller notes: Letterpress by Kennedy?
  - Food First Restaurant, Oakland [Chinese food], pre-1991 (415 area code) (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Dinah's Shack, Palo Alto, circa 1931 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bird Cage Cafe, Mountain View (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Hotel Saint Claire Luncheon, San Jose, 1933-08-16 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Touchdown Club of San Jose Testimonial Dinner Honoring University of Santa Clara Football Coaching Staff, Hotel Ste. Claire, 1950-04-24 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - The Trocadero, Hotel Del Rey, Santa Cruz (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Welcome to Santa Cruz. Published by Boyden Publishing Co., Stockton. Expires April 28, 1955 [advertising brochure, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Barreto's Famous Mexican Restaurant, Mission Inn, Monterey, circa 1943 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Alpine Tavern, Gonzales (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Series 4. California menus [unknown or multiple locations]
  - Blue Bell Coffee Shops (Salinas, Placerville, Monterey) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Hotel El Camino Real Grill Breakfast (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Rockaway Beach Inn, Rockaway Beach, Ca. [advertising placard, Pacifica?] (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Saddle & Sirloin (Palm Springs, Bakersfield, Studio City) (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Series 5. Los Angeles & Hollywood menus
  - Mme. Zucca Inn (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Bullock's Wilshire Luncheon (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Casa La Golondrina (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Jonanathan Club Victory Happy New Year, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Los Angeles Biltmore [opening], 1923-10-02 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Hotel Biltmore, 1930-12-26 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Katie Kohn's Kosher Restaurant, Real Hungarian, 1930-11-09 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Pig'N Whistle. 439 Broadway, 1930-10-31; 6714 Hollywood Blvd., 1930-11-02; 439 Broadway, 1931-06-09 [three menus], 1930-1931 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Herbert's [Xth Olympiad], 1932-02-26 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Banquet Honoring The Secretary of War and The Visiting Governors of the United States, Ambassador Hotel [annotated], 1933-07-28 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Twentieth Century-Fox Studios Banquet and Ball Honoring Convention Delegates, Coconut Grove, Ambassador Hotel, 1937-06-03 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Correspondence from Walter Leimert to his mother 6/4/1937 enclosed.
  - Mike Lyman's Grill (Los Angeles/Hollywood), 1942-03-13 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - The House of Murphy [humorous placemat with anti-Axis image and text], 1942-1945 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - The Los Angeles Junior Chamber of Commerce Salutes The Natural Gas Industry of Southern California [program with menu], 1957-12-03 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - State of Israel Commendation Dinner, L.A. Committee, State of Israel Bonds [Bevery Hilton], 1962-11-18 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    Inscribed "Kind Regards to Maurice Turner From Harry Truman 11-18-62"; Turner was Chairman of Building Funds and Endowments for the State of Israel Bonds, Los Angeles Committee.
  - Roosevelt Hollywood, Dinner, 1930-11-05 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Blossom Room, Roosevelt Hotel. Christmas, 1930-12-25 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Hollywood Roosevelt Hotel Dinner, 1933-11-08 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Hollywood Barn, pre-1933 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Gotham Delicatessen Shop, Hollywood (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Assistance League Tea Room, Hollywood (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Musso & Franks Grill, Hollywood, 1941-11-18 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Series 6. Southern California menus [San Luis Obispo - San Diego]
  - Motel Inn Coffee Shoppe, San Luis Obispo (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Rancho Bakersfield (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Occidental Hotel, Santa Barbara [handwritten dinner], 1873-02-28 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Hotel Potter, Santa Barbara [11 menus], 1909-1910 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Sky Room, Union Air Terminal, Burbank. Wines & Liquors (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Walt Disney Studio Restaurant, Burbank (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - The Coral Room, Bullock's Pasadena, 1949-09-27 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 73rd Annual Tournament of Roses Participants Dinner, Huntington-Sheridan Hotel, Viennese Room [Pasadena], 1961-12-07 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Las Flores Inn, Las Flores Canyon [Malibu] (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - The Ship Cage, Venice (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Sally's, Inglewood (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Frank Sebastian's New Cotton Club, Culver City (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - McDonnell's Plantation, Southgate, 1950-06-13 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Mission Cafeteria, Long Beach, 1931-12 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Solomon's, Palm Springs (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Bradley's Malt Shop, Santa Ana (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Mission Cafe, San Juan Capistrano (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Panama-Pacific Exposition Official Banquet, Cafe Cristobal, San Diego, 1915-01-01 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Grand Banquet Given By Al Malaikah Temple, AAONMS [Shriners], Hotel Del Coronado, Coronado, 1889-08-10 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Series 7. Non-California menus
  - Owl Drug Company [California, Oregon, Washington, Utah], after 1930 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Pantheon Saloon, Portland [Oregon], 1887-12-25 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Wigwam Inn, Indian River Park Souvenir Menu (Harbour Navigation Company, Vancouver, B.C.), 1930-07-01 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Schlesinger and Mayer: A New French Cafe, Chicago, 1898-01-13 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Chesapeake and Ohio, United Forces Menu (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Anglo-American Telegraph Company, Law Association Rooms. Liverpool Chamber of Commerce Dinner for The Layers of The Atlantic Cable [S.S. Great Eastern], 1866-10-01 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Luncheon In Honor of...The Kyoto Conference of the Institute of Pacific Relations by Viscount Eiichi Shibusawa at the Tokyo Kaikan, 1929-11-12 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Bombay Restaurant, Kowloon [inscribed], 1968 (Box 3, Folder 12)